PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and diligent Data Scientist with 2+ years of experience in building Artificial Intelligence (AI) & Machine Learning (ML) capabilities, utilizing Large Language Modeling (LLM) & Natural Language Processing (NLP) methodologies using SQL and Python. Proficient in deploying and evaluating models, collaborating with product engineers & user experience researchers, and presenting insights and impact to business owners.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Marriott International - Data Science Intern

June 2023 - Aug 2023

- Analyzed 18 million+ guest satisfaction surveys utilizing SQL and novel Python ML / NLP technologies. Generated recommendations to improve CX and operations across 31 hotel brands worldwide and 8500+ hotels.
- Facilitated communication across the Advanced Data Science Team and Voice of Customer Team. Communicated insights to business partners and non-technical stakeholders

Big Data at Berkeley - Data Consultant (Part-Time)

Sep 2022 - Jan 2024

• Classified mammography images by implementing ML / Computer Vision (Barlow Twins image embedding) and clustering techniques (k-means and spectral clustering) in Python and Azure. Project aimed to support breast cancer diagnostic processes. Project in partnership with Hologic.

PatternAI, Inc - Data Science (NLP) Intern

June 2022 - Aug 2022

- Enhanced new capabilities in product by leading research on keyword boosting and speaker identification methods. Conducted literature reviews, tested BERT embeddings, gaussian mixed models, convolutional neural networks, and other NLP methods. Keyword boosting research used as part of a demo to NVIDIA.
- Developed product requirement documents and product designs for PatternAl in the education sector.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Young Adult Literature Course - Lead Facilitator

Aug 2022 - May 2024

Managed logistics and communication for a course roster for 50+ students and department faculty.
Developed curriculum and activities for 10+ weeks of course content. Mentored other facilitators.

Asian Pacific American Student Development - Co-Lead Facilitator

Aug 2022 - May 2024

- Lead bi-weekly seminars on political topics within the Asian and Pacific Islander American community.
- Supported 20+ interns on individual community building and political education projects.

EDUCATION

Degree: Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science & Data Science. University of California, Berkeley. 2024.

Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Probability for Data Science, Causal Inference and Decisions, The Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs. **GPA**: 3.90/4.0.

CORE COMPETENCIES & TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Science, Python, SQL, R, Java, Tableau, Snowflake, Pandas, Scikit Learn, Jupyter Notebooks, Azure, AWS, Data Modeling, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Advanced Statistics, Written & Verbal Communication, Team Management, Leadership, Community Building and Organizing, Mentoring.

Certifications: All applications in Finance and Marketing (UPenn / Wharton); Fundamentals of Finance (UPenn / Wharton); Introduction to Financial Accounting (UPenn / Wharton)